Oh yeah, Aria-chan said she was at
the Cinderella Stars event, right?
But, I feel like I would've remembered
someone as gorgeous as her walking around.
Yeah, and no one was talking about
anyone else besides you two.
Maybe we were in the wrong
spot to hear about her?
Sorry 'bout the wait!
That was fast!
Ta-dah!
confused
Who're you?
Uh... I'm from Princess Chanel?
Think her name's Pearl?
It's "Princess Channel"!
And how are you Pearl-chan?!
Everything's wrong!
The hair, the colors, the outfit,
and you didn't change your makeup!
Huh?! How is it wrong?
I thought she had a blonde ponytail
and a black bikini-type thing?
Pearl-chan isn't blonde!
Her whole personality is based around
how much she hates her red hair!
Wait, really?
I don't know anything about her,
I just know the anime's real popular.
GAHHH
Cosplaying popular characters
is how you get famous, right?
She doesn't have a ponytail!
You can't even call this cosplay!
AAAAAAAAA
I take back all those heartfelt things I said!
You agree, right, Riri...
Aria-chan...
Yeah?!
You're wasting your potential!
Huh?
Cosplay is so much more fun than this!
Your Way, My Way
She doesn't have a ponytail!
You can't even call this cosplay!
I take back all those heartfelt things I said!
Maybe I shouldn't have dragged
a random stranger into their room...
Cosplay's about taking a 2D design and
finding a way to skillfully recreate it in 3D!
When you wear your cosplay,
you get in the groove with your favorite character!
In the groove?
After hours of hard work,
when you make other fans
super happy to see you...
It's utter bliss!
Is it?
You're a diamond in the rough, Aria-chan!
With your looks,
you can be any character you want!
You have a world of endless possibilities!
Oh, Aria-chan... Please, I beg of you...
Will you try cosplaying our way, just once?
I promise, you'll shine brighter than ever!
I'd love that!
First, let's get you acquainted
with a bunch of famous anime!
We'll also watch all the anime airing this season!
Wait, don't those air way past midnight?
How else are we going to get you
to go down the rabbit hole?
Huh?
Don't worry. You'll like it in the rabbit hole.
Sorry, Nonoa.
Once she gets started,
she can't be stopped...
I get it.
It's probably why I like her so much, anyway.
You had the courage to go out and cosplay.
That's enough to make you an ally.
A friend.
Will you be my friend?
Yes! Of course I'll be your friend!
She took me in as a friend.
I've got no right to stop her
doing that for someone else.
And maybe if she starts liking otaku stuff, too...
I can be friends with her,
despite the gyaru thing.
I'll need your help too, Nono-pi!
Stop calling me that!
And give me some personal space!
Girls' Locker Room
But, it's gonna take time for me to get there.
Before you change,
can I take a closer look at your costumes?
Sure, if it'll help you learn something!
If Ririsa-chan is cool with it, I guess I am, too.
Yay!
Are these your real boobs?
Yup!
Can I touch them?
Are you crazy?! No!
Go ahead!
What?!
I don't want people to touch me
and think it's just a costume.
I want my costume to be so realistic
that people think I'm really Liliel,
even when they touch me!
Okay, lemme try.
Hands off!
What?! But she said it was okay!
To touch her costume!
I-it's fine, really!
Sorry, you were just so cute,
I couldn't help myself.
You wanna touch 'em too, don'tcha, Nono-pi?
Would you, uh, like to touch them?
D-did they feel like Liliel's?
Y-yeah...
Like marshmallows,
or meat buns, they're just...
Angelic.
Boobs can be angelic?
I'm so jealous.
Like, both of you have great figures.
Straight out of a manga.
I'm all flat and angular.
No way! You're so thin and slender,
just like an anime character!
I'm all short and stumpy and thick.
What?! But that's so much more attractive!
Yeah! I'm all muscle.
I wish I looked more feminine.
Wait, but you have the body of a model!
But Ririsa's soft and curvy,
and you're slim and elegant.
The grass is greener on the other side, huh?
There's no such thing as a perfect body...
But with cosplay,
you can change your figure however you want!
That's one of the great things about cosplay!
You're right.
I don't really think about my
figure when I'm cosplaying.
Sorry for interrupting your shoot today!
It's okay! We still had a great time.
Oh, hey, you should come to our club sometime!
Wait, really? I'm so there!
Manga Club
Okay, girls!
Today, we're dragging Aria-chan down the
rabbit hole with our first anime viewing party!
Thanks!
I can't believe the principal said this was okay.
I heard you got another cute cosplayer to join,
so I worked my magic on him!
I treated it like a "joint band rehearsal."
Are we a band now?
Amano-san is a national-level competitor, yes?
It would be good for her to
practice with others at her level.
We don't do competitions, though...
I wish you the best of luck
at your summer tournament!
Is he talking about Comiket?
I'd stick around,
but I've got meetings today.
Thank you, Sensei!
She's a newbie, right?
Go easy on her.
Don't worry, we will!
By the way, Ririsa-sensei,
what's this "rabbit hole"
you're gonna drag me into?
Am I about to get punked or something?
You wouldn't be here if we were about to prank you.
Oh, right, duh.
LOOOOOM
The "rabbit hole" is the deep,
dark pit of otakudom.
Once you're hooked, you fall in.
The more you watch,
the deeper you go,
until the light is blotted out by anime and manga.
Oh, Geez!
Why'd you have to make it sound so scary?
So what, is that darkness where you all live now?
Yep.
Yeppers.
Should I be worried?!
There's no right way to cosplay,
but we want you to try doing it our way,
just once.
To find a character you like,
and learn how fun cosplay can be!
First, you'll watch a bunch
of different classics,
then make a cosplay
of your favorite character...
You sure you're not just trying
to turn me into an otaku?
Without further ado,
allow me to introduce you to
the professor assisting us!
Hi, there.
I've picked out a selection to start with.
Call me Professor Okumura.
Yeah, yeah, I know you.
You're Ririsa's boyfriend.
We're not dating!
What?! You're joking!
You guys totally act like a couple, though!
I totally assumed you were together!
That thought didn't even pass through my head...
I'm only into 2D girls.
I'd never date a 3D girl like her.
No idea what that means,
but now I know you're a real creep.
Right, then!
Let's start with one of the Liliel anime.
Senpai, if we wanted to watch all 312 episodes,
that would take us four full days.
312 episodes?!
Holy crap, don't scare me like that!
That's without eating or sleeping, too.
There is an entire spinoff dedicated to Liliel,
which is practically our bible.
But, would it be strange to start with the spinoff?
Allow me to give you my expert otaku opinion.
You can start any series wherever you want!
Missed the first episode?
You can still watch the rest of the season!
Don't know the manga but think
the cover for Volume 6 is sick? Buy it!
Your favorite actor said they liked it?
That's a perfectly good reason to get into it!
Plus, the first season's only 13 episodes,
so we can watch it in four hours!
We're gonna watch anime for four hours?!
That's longer than most sports practices!
I'm giving you homework, too.
Ririsa, you're scaring me.
Don't worry, once you get into it,
you can spend your entire
summer break watching anime
without remembering to eat or drink.
This is gonna
be fun.
Nono-pi, you're the worst one here.
The action scene in the first episode is so good,
you'll think it was made for a movie!
Please enjoy the internationally-acclaimed
animation work of master Nakamura.
No idea what you're talking about,
but I'm ready to go.
LILIEL!
Okay, no shouting at the screen!
Movie theater rules, got it?
Right. Sorry.
Sorry.
That last line of hers was foreshadowed
way back in the early episodes!
Cool.
She doesn't seem into it.
Maybe this anime is too
tough for a gyaru to get into.
We should've started with a romantic comedy.
Let's have faith in our beloved Liliel!
Y-you're right.
Aria-chan...
Is this boring you?
Huh? No, it's good.
Wait, really?!
Just, I dunno...
I've been sitting around for too long.
Doesn't it make you wanna
go outside and walk around?
Go... Outside?
Huh? Why would we go outside?
Yeah. Why?
You're acting like we're in a
zombie movie or something.
Sorry, Aria-chan.
I-if you can't make it through watching this,
then there's no way you
can learn anything from Ririsa.
This is a piece of cake for me.
I can do it!
I love Ririsa's passion.
I know she's got the right idea!
I'm dead set on cosplaying with you two!
You're awesome cosplayers!
She's not even an otaku, though.
Why is she so dead set on this?
There's no going back! I'm doing this!
All we're doing is watching some anime...
I've got you now!
Get away from here.
I'll hold it back,
even if it costs my life...
Don't be ridiculous!
You think we'd sacrifice you just to escape?!
Well, if we're going to die anyways,
we may as well do it as a group.
Wait, that's the end?
How can they end it there?!
Things were just getting intense!
What happens next?!
Hello?
Anything I say would be a spoiler!
I want to tell you so bad,
but I can't say a single word!
O-okay.
Liliel!
No! She can't...
This can't be happening!
HUFF HUFF HUFF HUFF
Otaku who now enjoy the first
reactions of first time viewers
LILIEL!
That was so good!
I'm so glad you liked it!
I never knew anime could
make me cry like this!
I'm glad it resonated with you!
I was worried a fantasy show
would be too tough to get into.
Nah, it kinda reminded me of a manga
I read when I was a kid.
Oh, good.
Wonder what manga that was.
We'll watch some old classics
and new popular anime,
so you can find a character you like!
Sounds good!
I wish every class was this fun, Sensei!
It's so much fun.
I get to see my friends every week,
and watch anime together...
Don't cry, Nono-pi!
We can hang out whenever you want.
We're friends, after all!
BA-DUMP
can't resist the word 'friend'
I know what'll turn that frown upside down.
Let's go bowling,
hit up an all-you-can-eat place,
then finish it off with some karaoke!
Are you trying to kill me?
Okay, let's call it for today.
Okay!
Nono-pi, let's walk back together!
We can hit up the stores by the station!
How do you have this much energy?
I didn't really get this one.
Nono-pi almost died laughing, though.
It might be a little too meta.
It's hard to get it if you're not already an otaku.
Yeah, let's stay away from
anything with too many inside jokes.
Penetrate!
That was a fun anime!
Yeah, first time I've seen it, too.
Okumura-senpai really knows how to pick them.
Here you go!
Wait, you got me one, too?
I've never had it before.
excited
Thanks!
I'm so full... My blood sugar is so high...
You barely took a baby sip!
W-wait, what did I do this time?
You said this was a new anime?
The art is more polished than older anime,
but there's less animation overall.
The plot was pretty interesting, though.
I can't believe she's already
doing such in-depth analysis...
All the old ones we've watched
were masterpieces of their time,
so you might be a little biased.
Oh, yeah.
And animation quality isn't everything.
Anime is all a product of its time,
and some older shows haven't aged that well.
But, you should watch some older
animation from Western studios.
It's shockingly good.
We've seen a lot of anime now.
Were there any shows or
characters that stood out to you?
You're right, we've watched a lot...
But, I think I liked the first
one we watched most of all.
That's the one you guys are super into, too.
All our hard work paid off!
I'd call that a win, Ririsa!
Totally!
Plus, then I'd get to do a cosplay
group with you guys, right?
Y-yeah, we could.
So which character would you wanna be?
Ririsa does Liliel, and Nono-pi does Nokiel,
and they're both in the Angelic
Airborne Defense Squadron, yeah?
If you like Liliel,
then you could cosplay her this time...
Nah, I already know who I want to be...
Her.
Ariel!
Yup, Ariel!
You'd make an awesome Ariel, Aria-chan!
Did you pick her 'cause your names are the same?
What? No!
Just, like... I dunno how to put it.
She looks a whole lot like me, don't you think?
That's that, then!
You need an Ariel costume!
You can make it by hand,
or you can commission or
buy an already-made one.
I want to make it!
I won't stand out in anything else!
Got it! I'll help you do it!
She cares so much about the most random things.
It's so confusing.
I'll show you the ropes,
and we'll debut our group
at the next big event!
Yeah!
I had so much fun today.
"Twenty cosplayers that didn't
make the Rising Stars list..."
Is that Aria-chan?
Why'd she wear an obscure
cosplay to her first event?
She doesn't know much about manga
and said she would do
popular characters to get famous.
Or did she make that all up?!
What's going on?
A true diamond in the rough:
this is apparently her first cosplay,
and it very much shows.
I asked what series she was from,
but had no idea what
it was until I looked it up.
Why cosplay such an obscure character?
Wait, that's Melia from VB, Valkyrie Battle.
I haven't thought about that series in forever!
It was in the first Jump magazine I ever bought,
back in first grade,
like ten years ago?
That was before I got into Liliel.
Whoa! That makes it pretty old, then.
I was super into it for some reason.
I actually sent my first fan
letter to the VB mangaka.
Cool!
But I got a weird letter back.
Wait, you got a letter back?!
That's extra cool!
Thank you for your letter, Okumura-kun.
But please don't tell your friends you like my manga.
They'll make fun of you.
Whoa...
Talk about worst case scenario.
I wasn't online back then,
so I hadn't heard the rumors,
but people were all saying the manga
was a knockoff of the Ashford Chronicles.
It ended up getting canceled after just ten chapters.
As a kid,
I was confused how such an
awesome manga ended in just two volumes.
I don't blame him, though.
That would've been a lot to deal with.
I bought the volumes,
but I haven't read them in a long time.
It brings back too many bad memories.
I'm pretty sure I brought them here at some point...
Yeah, here it is.
Okay, then why was Aria-chan
cosplaying from that manga?
Hey hey, people!
Wait, what're you guys up to?
Why do you have a copy of VB?
That's from my first event!
I didn't know that guy was a big deal.
Aria-chan, why'd you cosplay from
this ancient, obscure manga?
Didn't you want to get famous?
Seriously, there's so much about
you that doesn't make sense!
Could you tell us why you even
want to cosplay so badly?
Nah, that's kinda personal!
Says the person who's always
in our personal space!
Now she doesn't want to get personal?!
I was just starting to trust her, too!
This is why I hate gyaru...
No, stop that.
Maybe Aria-chan and I have some disconnect,
just like I did with Ririsa-chan at first.
I should hear her out.
Then, I'll tell her how I feel.
Aria-chan, why can't you tell us?
Is it too hard to talk about?
Not really, it's just kinda boring.
Boring?! But I want to hear it!
Yeah, but I feel like friends need to keep
some distance between them, y'know?
If I told you everything right off the bat,
we'd get way too close,
like family close,
and we'd always be
oversharing and asking for comfort.
That's no fun for anyone.
Friends are people you should have fun with,
not emotional punching bags, y'know?
I hadn't thought of it that way.
Aria-chan's got a lot
more experience with friendship,
and that's where she's coming from.
I'm glad I heard her out.
But, now I need to tell her what I think!
Maybe that's what normal friends are like...
But, I was raised on shonen manga,
and they taught me that
friends tell each other everything!
Their past, their feelings, their real selves!
I want to be friends with you, Aria-chan,
so I want to know why you want to cosplay!
N-Nono-pi...
Nonoa-chan...
You guys wanna know, too?
If you don't mind telling us.
I don't mind, just... How do I say this?
My dad's the author of this manga.
What?!
Your dad's a manga-ka?!
He's the author of Valkyrie Battle?!
Comrades in (Cosplay) Arms